Contact

+36302512977 (Mobile) csongvai.roland@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ rolandcsongvai (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Project Management
Product Development
R&D

Languages

English (Full Professional)

German (Professional Working)

Hungarian (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Green Belt Six Sigma // Lean, DMAIC, DFSS

Intro to Self-Driving Cars Nanodegree

ISO 9001:2008 Internal Auditor

ISO 13485:2012 Internal Auditor

Introduction to Enterprise Architecture

Honors-Awards

GE Commitment! Award

Young Scientist Award on national level in Hungary, 3rd place

Young Scientist Award on local level in Hungary, 1st place

Young Scientist Award on local level in Hungary, 2nd place

Acknowledgement by the Rector of the Budapest University of Technology and Economics

Publications

GUI, clicking on you

Developing a Proactive Reality Environment for Conceptual Design Evaluation of e-banking solutions

Roland Csongvai

Dealing with System Safety in Autonomous Driving Context at Volvo Cars

Gothenburg, Västra Götaland County, Sweden

Summary

Confident, visionary, committed, & qualified professional for delivering results. *** 10+ years of the listed versatile challenges are demonstrating a proven track record for providing strategic, tactical, and operative solutions to high-profile organizations in the field of Integrated Product Design, Product Services, Product Service Systems in a wide range of industries e.g.: consumer goods, automotive/transport., IT etc.. *** Mastering skills that extend beyond the strict definition of "design"; the term integrated means a systematic approach to product-/service- (portfolio) at all stages of the theirs life cycle and related business processes such as; needs assessment prior to embarking on development, & through conceptualisation, "prototyping" and product/service marketing as well as manufacturing & repair/recycling. *** Suited with extensive knowledge to perform complex "design" activities with modern methods and advanced technologies, & how to plan, - execute and - manage complex product-/process- (portfolio) development/ production with multidisciplinary teams in matrixed organisations at cross-border environments.

Experience

Business Innovation Design
Partner at Business Innovation Design Consultancy
February 2016 - Present

Hungary, Switzerland, The Netherlands, Italy, Belgium, Spain, France, Malaysia

Ownership to build Business Innovation Design Consultancy Organisation in Hungary. *** Building presence in Europe. *** Provide solid business innovation design consultancy services for Companies are having wicked problems; facing with VUCA - volatility, uncertainty, complexity and ambiguity at once on their own or targeted market landscape what is constantly changing at a rapid peace with unpredictability. *** Business Innovation Design (BID) seamlessly connects various disciplines in a framework tied by methods and

The future of on-demand, personalised content in the mobile communication

The future of on-demand, personalised content in the mobile communication - extended

Patents

High Intensity Discharge Lamp with Ignition Aid - Covers 50%+ of the recent GE Lighting CMH lamp portfolio with an annual volume of multi-million pcs (2012 -)

tools. Every block consists of its own tools that gives decision-making clarity from various perspectives. It's modular approach enables the utilization of multiple processes designed for continuous innovation.

Volvo Cars

Autonomous Driving Redundant Platform Program System Safety Lead, Active Safety

February 2018 - February 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Gothenburg, Sweden

CLAAS

Portfolio-/Program-/Project Manager, Business Unit Grain December 2016 - October 2017 (11 months)

Törökszentmiklós

Holding joint overall responsibility with the Project Sponsor for the achievement of the project objective(s) towards C-level Executives. *** Planning & directing of the portfolio-/program-/project. *** Achieving the objectives defined in the project contract for the overall portfolio-/program-/project. *** Acting as a "fixed-appointment entrepreneur" for the portfolio-/program-/project. *** Integrating the necessary companies/sites within CLAAS and beyond. *** Ensure integrity with the CLAAS Product Development Process (CPDP).

CLAAS

Functional Safety Manager, Business Unit Grain October 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Törökszentmiklós

Ensure product Quality by Functional Safety Management. ***
Coordinating compliance with the methods and processes for functional safety. *** Analysing the impact of ISO26262 for specific a portfolio-/program-/project and creating Functional Safety awareness across departments. ***
Performing safety management activities according to relevant standards during all project phases including preliminary hazard analysis, DFMEA, FMEDA, qualitative and quantitative fault tree analysis, etc. *** Developing safety architectures and safety plans to ensure compliance with ISO26262. *** Leading and coordinating the creation of functional safety documentation according ISO26262. *** Cascading safety requirements to the systems, subsystems, and component levels in product portfolio. *** Collaborate with portfolio-/program-/project managers, development teams, Suppliers and Customers on Functional Safety. *** Conducting reviews.

CLAAS

Grain & Flex Headers R&D Group Leader, Business Unit Grain August 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 3 months)

Törökszentmiklós

Line manager position. *** Accountability for System Engineers, Main Group Leaders & Designers. *** Managing resources - training, hiring, etc..

BorgWarner Inc.
Program Manager, Emissions Systems
October 2014 - July 2016 (1 year 10 months)
Oroszlány

A highly visible and strategically-oriented position. *** Direct responsibility for the management of global and local programs considering one or multiple Customers who are doing businesses with a particular or multiple BorgWarner productions plants. *** Organising, coordinating and executing an extensive program management regiment aimed for maximizing the business potential, with much focus on developing relationships with the Customers as the single point of contact (SPOC). *** Enabling new business opportunities. *** Working at all levels of the organization in order to build a business case for new programs. *** Gaining the commitment of Staff members (including C-level in global context as well) for allocating the necessary resources (Supply Chain, Application Engineering, Key Account Management, Reliability Engineering, Finance, Manufacturing & Quality Engineering) and for providing management direction for the customer programs. *** Focusing on launch management, cost management, customer intelligence, and communications based on the sequential steps of the BorgWarner's Advanced Product Quality Planning (APQP) process.

Valeo

Program/Project Manager, Comfort & Driving Assistance Systems/ Interior Controls

April 2014 - June 2014 (3 months)

Veszprém

An Operational Manager role in New Product Introduction (NPI/NPDP). ***
Exclusively empowered by the Product Group-/Regional Operation-/Product
Line General Manager. *** Accountable for quality, timing, gross margin,
project cost and customer satisfaction/communication as SPOC. *** Leading
the responsible Project Organisation consist with R&D, Supply Chain, Process.

Purchasing, Quality, Marketing, Launch Teams. *** 250+ stakeholders. *** Programs budgeted to 8 figures [€].

GRUNDFOS Holding A/S

New Development Introduction Manager, Development & Engineering (D&E) Central Europe

January 2013 - February 2014 (1 year 2 months)

Székesfehérvár

R&D chain's specific NPDP activities (R&D, internal-/external partners, relevant sites). *** 80+ stakeholders. *** Defining & requesting deliveries from all relevant functions in the value chain. *** Correct timing and alignment of activities between the technical functions. *** Establish & operate within costand investment budget with 7 figures number in [€]. *** Full line report to the Business Development Organisation.

GE Lighting

Design Engineer/Project Manager, Global Lighting Technology HID/CMH

May 2010 - January 2013 (2 years 9 months)

Budapest

Engineering-, project management-tasks at New Product Introduction (NPI) & process-innovation.

Ateknea Solutions formerly MFKK Ltd. R&D Engineer/Scientific Manager May 2009 - February 2010 (10 months) Budapest

Proposal writing in EU FP7. *** Engineering-, management tasks, business development duties, scientific analyses of emerging technologies and trends. *** 1,5 - 4 MM € worth international R&D projects. *** Coordinating a consortium of 10 members (30 Stakeholders).

Nokia, T-Mobile Hungary, Holidaycafé.hu, etc. Assignment Based Project Contribution/Entrepreneurship 1999 - 2010 (11 years)

Hungary, (France),

Projects listed below.

Education

Budapest University of Technology and Economics Master of Business Administration (M.B.A.), Finance Specialization · (2012 - 2019)

Technische Universiteit Delft Guest Researcher, Faculty of Industrial Design Engineering - Design

Engineering · (2006 - 2007)

Budapest University of Technology and Economics
Ph.D. - Intermitted studies, Faculty of Electronics Engineering - Electronics
Technology · (2005 - 2006)

Budapest University of Technology and Economics

M.Sc. in Industrial Design Engineering, Faculty of Mechanical Engineering Integrated Product Design · (1997 - 2004)